Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we have a cold lesson.
我是Catherine，今天我们有一个关于寒冷的课程。
That's right.
没错。
It's the winter season and of course it gets cold in a lot of different places around the
现在是冬季，当然世界上很多地方都会变冷，
world and so we're going to talk about heating.
所以我们要谈谈取暖。
Okay, this is very important but before we do get started, we have a very important word
好的，这非常重要，但在开始之前，我们有一个非常重要的词
to preview in Vocabulary Preview.
要在词汇预览中先看一下。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Alright, so we're going to preview the word freezing.
好的，我们要预览一下“freezing”这个词。
It is freezing today by the way so this is very appropriate.
顺便说一句，今天真是冷得要命，所以这个词很应景。
Freezing means very, very, very cold.
“Freezing”意思是极其、极其、极其冷。
Okay, it is freezing.
好的，就是冷得要命。
Okay, so it's very cold.
好的，所以非常冷。
It's freezing today.
今天冷得要命。
It's so cold in fact you can't have water outside because the water will become ice.
实际上冷到你不能把水放在外面，因为水会变成冰。
It will freeze.
它会结冰。
Okay, great word.
好的，这个词很棒。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the very first time.
那么让我们第一次听一下我们的对话。
It's freezing in here.
这里冷得要命。
Can I turn up the heat?
我能把暖气开大点吗？
Don't touch that thermostat.
别碰那个恒温器。
You don't pay the bills around here.
这里又不是你付账单。
Dad, are you serious?
爸，你是认真的吗？
What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it?
如果我们不能用中央供暖，那装它有什么用？
Look, I can see my breath.
看，我都能看到自己的呼吸了。
Put on a sweater.
穿上件毛衣。
I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly.
我不会因为有点凉就让你把我的取暖费账单搞上去。
Dad, I'm going to catch a cold.
爸，我会感冒的。
When I was your age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do.
我像你这么大的时候，我父母可没有像你这样的中央供暖。
We had a furnace in the center of the living room and that was it.
我们客厅中间只有一个炉子，就那样。
We used it to cook, heat the house, and even dry our clothes.
我们用那个炉子做饭、取暖，甚至烘干衣服。
We never caught a cold.
我们从来没感冒过。
You should be grateful.
你应该知足了。
Alright, we're back and this is actually what a lot of dads are like I think around the
好的，我们回来了，这实际上就是很多爸爸的样子，我想全世界都差不多。
world.
Yep, my dad definitely liked to keep the heat low in the house.
是的，我爸爸绝对喜欢把家里的暖气调低。
Alright, so we'll talk about that a little bit later but let's take a look at some four
好的，我们稍后会再谈这个，但先来看看今天的“语言要点”中的四个词。
words on Language Takeaway today.
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Well, this first word is important for anyone who has a home with heating.
嗯，第一个词对家里有暖气的人来说很重要。
It's called a thermostat.
它叫恒温器。
Alright, a thermostat.
好的，一个恒温器。
What is a thermostat?
什么是恒温器？
A thermostat is a dial or like a device on the wall that tells you how hot or how
恒温器是墙上的一种刻度盘或装置，用来显示温度高低。
cold the house is.
这房子真冷。
It's like a thermometer for your house.
它就像你家的温度计一样。
Okay, so you can move the thermostat, the temperature to make the house warmer or colder,
好的，你可以调节恒温器，也就是温度，让房子变得更暖或更冷。
right?
对吧？
Right, so if it says it's 20 degrees and I think that's too cold, I can turn the thermostat
好的，如果显示是20度，而我觉得太冷了，我可以调一下恒温器。
up to 23 degrees.
最高可达23度。
Alright, and well very much related to a thermostat and what this device does is our next word,
好的，这个词和我们刚才说的恒温器以及它的功能密切相关，这就是我们的下一个词。
central heating.
中央供暖。
Right, so if you have central heating, you have a thermostat.
对，所以如果你有中央供暖系统，你就会有恒温器。
It's the way to control the heat and central heating means that you have one heater for
这是控制温度的方式，中央供暖意味着你只有一个加热器。
the whole house and so the air comes into all the different rooms.
整个房子都是这样，所以空气能进入所有不同的房间。
So not many places in China have this but for example in the United States, in Canada,
所以在中国很多地方没有这个，但比如在美国、加拿大，
it is very common.
这很常见。
Okay, so your house or your apartment building will have central heating and then you can
好的，那么你的房子或公寓楼会有中央供暖系统，然后你就可以
control how cold or warm the house is with thermostats.
用恒温器来控制房子的冷热。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good and well our next word is related to temperature and it's chilly.
很好。接下来这个词和温度有关，是“chilly”（寒冷的）。
Chilly, okay, so there's a big difference between chilly and freezing.
冷，好吧，所以“chilly”和“freezing”之间有很大的区别。
Freezing means very very very cold.
Freezing 意思是特别特别特别冷。
Chilly means a little cold.
Chilly 意思是有点冷。
Right, so it's a little cold.
对，是有点冷。
It's a bit chilly.
有点凉。
Right, so it's a bit chilly today, I'm going to wear a hat.
好的，今天有点冷，我打算戴顶帽子。
Okay, if it's freezing, I'm going to wear a hat and mittens and a scarf and coat and
好的，如果天寒地冻，我就戴上帽子、手套、围巾，再穿上大衣。
boots.
靴子。
Right, so if it's a bit chilly, it's not very cold and well moving on, the dad mentioned
好的，如果只是有点凉，那就不算很冷。好了，继续往下，爸爸提到了
about him having a furnace when he was young.
他年轻时家里有个火炉。
That's right, the dad had a furnace in his house and the furnace is a way to heat your
没错，这位爸爸家里有个火炉，火炉是用来取暖的。
house.
房子。
It's like a stove.
它就像个炉子。
So yeah, just consider it like a big oven, right?
所以，你就把它想象成一个巨大的烤箱，对吧？
Maybe you've seen it in the old movies where you would have to throw firewood into the
也许你在老电影里见过，得往里面扔柴火。
furnace to make it heat up the house.
让炉子给房子供暖。
Exactly, and so this is very common in older homes and not very common in apartments.
没错，这在老房子里很常见，但在公寓里就不太常见了。
Right, and well, that's all the words we have for language takeaway today.
好的，以上就是我们今天语言小课堂的全部词汇。
Why don't we listen to this chilly dialogue again.
我们为什么不重新听一遍这段冷飕飕的对话呢？
It's freezing in here.
这里冷死了。
Can I turn up the heat?
我能把暖气开大点吗？
Don't touch that thermostat.
别碰那个恒温器。
You don't pay the bills around here.
这儿又不是你付账单。
Dad, are you serious?
爸，你是认真的吗？
What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it?
有中央供暖却不能用，那还有什么意义？
Look, I can see my breath.
看，我都能看见自己呼出的气了。
Put on a sweater.
穿上件毛衣。
I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly.
我不会因为有点冷就让你把我的取暖费账单搞得老高。
Dad, I'm going to catch a cold.
爸，我会感冒的。
When I was your age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do.
我像你这么大的时候，我爸妈可没有你们现在这样的中央供暖。
We had a furnace in the center of the living room and that was it.
我们客厅中间只有一个炉子，就那样。
We used it to cook, heat the house, and even dry our clothes.
我们用那个炉子做饭、取暖，甚至烘干衣服。
We never caught a cold.
我们从没感冒过。
You should be grateful.
你应该知足了。
Alright we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we have prepared for you three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在我们为你准备了流利度训练中的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay, so this first phrase is related to thermostat.
好的，第一个短语和恒温器有关。
So thermostat like we said is like a thermometer but we can control the temperature.
恒温器就像温度计，但我们可以控制温度。
So if we want to make the temperature hotter, we turn up the thermostat.
所以如果我们想让温度更高，我们就调高恒温器。
So this is a phrasal verb, to turn up the heat.
这是一个动词短语，to turn up the heat（调高暖气）。
You could say this about heat.
你可以用这个来说暖气。
You could say this about noise too.
你也可以用这个来说噪音。
Can you turn up the radio?
你能把收音机开大点吗？
Turn up the volume.
把音量调大。
So it's to increase.
所以它的意思是增加。
To increase, to make bigger or warmer or louder.
增加，让东西变大、变暖或变响。
Alright and if we wanted to decrease the temperature in the thermostat, you would say...
好的，如果我们想降低恒温器的温度，你会说……
Turn down.
调低。
Turn down the heat.
把暖气调低。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's too hot in here.
所以这里太热了。
Can you please turn down the heat?
你能把暖气调低吗？
Alright, very good.
好的，非常好。
And our next phrase is, well the dad was talking about the bills and how expensive it is to
我们的下一个短语是，爸爸在谈论账单以及使用恒温器有多贵，
use the thermostat and he said, I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill.
他说，我不会让你把我的取暖费账单搞得老高。
Okay, so a bill is like you know, something that you pay.
好的，账单就像你要付的东西。
It's money.
是钱。
And so in this case, I don't want you to run up the bill.
所以在这种情况下，我不想让你把账单搞大。
That means to increase the amount of money I have to spend.
这意味着增加我必须支付的金额。
So maybe if you leave your television on all night, you're running up your electricity
所以如果你整晚开着电视，你就是在增加你的电费
bill.
账单。
Exactly.
没错。
And if you leave it on 10 hours a day, you run up the phone bill and your mother kills
如果你每天开10小时，你就是在增加电话费，然后你妈妈会杀了
you.
你。
Right.
对。
Alright and well the daughter was complaining about her catching a cold.
好的，女儿在抱怨她感冒了。
To catch a cold.
感冒。
Alright, so remember this.
好的，记住这个。
A cold is when you have maybe a runny nose and a cough and a sore throat.
感冒就是你可能流鼻涕、咳嗽和喉咙痛。
It usually happens when the weather changes.
通常发生在天气变化的时候。
But we don't get a cold.
但我们不说“得到感冒”。
You catch a cold.
而是说“染上感冒”。
Okay.
好的。
And remember like in baseball, you throw and catch.
记住，就像在棒球里，你投球和接球。
It's something that's fast.
这是很快的事情。
Alright, so you catch a cold.
好的，所以你说“染上感冒”。
What about the flu?
那流感呢？
Do you get the flu or catch the flu?
你是说“得到流感”还是“染上流感”？
So you can't catch a flu but you can catch a cold.
所以你不能说“染上流感”，但可以说“染上感冒”。
Just remember this phrase.
记住这个短语。
To catch a cold.
染上感冒。
I caught the cold.
我染上了感冒。
To catch a cold or I caught a cold.
染上感冒或我染上了感冒。
It's almost like if I have it, I can throw it to you Marco.
这就像如果我有，我可以把它扔给你，Marco。
Achoo!
阿嚏！
And you catch it.
然后你接住了它。
Right, because it's in the air, the virus.
对，因为病毒在空气中。
Yeah, it passes very quickly.
是的，它传播得很快。
Alright, very good.
好的，非常好。
So an interesting dialogue.
所以这是一个有趣的对话。
Let's listen to it one last time.
让我们最后听一遍。
It's freezing in here.
这里冷死了。
Can I turn up the heat?
我能把暖气开大点吗？
Don't touch that thermostat.
别碰那个恒温器。
You don't pay the bills around here.
这里不是你付账单。
Dad, are you serious?
爸，你是认真的吗？
What's the point of having central heating if we can't use it?
如果我们不能用中央供暖，那装它有什么用？
Look, I can see my breath.
看，我都能看到自己的呼吸了。
Put on a sweater.
穿上毛衣。
I'm not going to let you run up my heating bill just because it's a bit chilly.
我不会让你因为有点冷就把我的暖气费搞大。
Dad, I'm going to catch a cold.
爸，我会感冒的。
When I was your age, my parents didn't have central heating like you do.
我像你这么大的时候，我父母没有像你这样的中央供暖。
We had a furnace in the center of the living room and that was it.
我们客厅中间只有一个炉子，就那样。
We used it to cook, heat the house and even dry our clothes.
我们用那个炉子做饭、取暖，甚至烘干衣服。
We never caught a cold.
我们从来没感冒过。
You should be grateful.
你应该感恩。
Alright, we're back and well you mentioned about the thermostat and your dad actually
好的，我们回来了，你提到了恒温器，还有你爸爸实际上
controlling the heating at home.
在家里控制暖气。
Was this the case like this in this scenario?
在这个场景里是这样吗？
It was.
是的。
Sometimes we would have to wear more clothes because we didn't want to run up the bill.
有时候我们不得不穿更多衣服，因为我们不想把账单搞大。
We had a special situation in my house because I'm from Chicago and it's very cold in the
我家有个特殊情况，因为我来自芝加哥，那里冬天非常冷，
winters in Chicago but we had a fireplace.
但我们有个壁炉。
Even if it was very cold, we always had firewood and we could put on the fire in the fireplace
即使很冷，我们总有柴火，可以点燃壁炉
to keep warm so everyone would stay in the living room and read and listen to music and
取暖，所以大家都会待在客厅里看书、听音乐，
just relax.
放松一下。
Now I heard that because when you're burning wood, it causes some pollution.
我听说因为烧木头会造成一些污染。
In some cities, it's banned to actually turn on or to have a fireplace.
在一些城市，实际上禁止使用或拥有壁炉。
That's right.
没错。
But in Chicago, you can still do it.
但在芝加哥，你仍然可以这样做。
Absolutely.
当然。
And in most of the states, you can.
而且在大多数州，你都可以。
Although a lot of people in new houses, they don't have real fireplaces.
尽管很多新房子的人没有真正的壁炉。
They have electric fireplaces.
他们有电壁炉。
So you can use a light switch to turn on your fire.
所以你可以用开关来打开你的火。
It's not a real fire.
那不是真正的火。
It's just a glowing light.
只是发光的灯。
It's very fancy.
很 fancy。
Alright, well very good.
好的，非常好。
This is an interesting lesson especially because the winter season is coming up and well everyone
这是一节有趣的课，尤其是因为冬天快到了，而且每个人
is cold.
都很冷。
So we hope you enjoyed it and if you have any questions, any doubts, you can come to
所以我们希望你喜欢，如果你有任何问题或疑问，你可以来
our website EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能见到你。
Happy studies and stay warm.
学习愉快，保持温暖。
Alright.
好的。
See you soon.
再见。